# Sergious Beryl

🗣 Bangalore, Karnataka | 🛈 Phone: 7904938661 | 🖂 E-mail: berylsergious@gmail.com | 🛈 LinkedIn: sergious-beryl-b7b005161

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Equipped with master's degree in international Transportation and Logistics & 2 years and 10 months experience as Quality Engineer/ Product Specialist in supply chain domain. Enthusiastic about deploying my skill set for a company providing digital solutions & driving IT transformations in business processes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Blume Global (A Subsidiary of WiseTech Global), Bengaluru

Quality Engineer | Apr 2024 - Present

- Automated UI validation for logistics web apps (Shipment Tracking, Order Management) using Selenium WebDriver within a BDD/Hybrid framework (Cucumber, Java, TestNG) implementing Page Object Model (POM)
- Proficient in Java programming concepts (OOPs, Collections, Exception Handling).
- Analysed real-time data using MongoDB and MySQL, identifying critical patterns and trends that improved estimated delivery prediction accuracy by ~ 5% and improving logistic feasibility calculations.
- Performed API testing using Postman and Swagger, validating REST endpoints (GET/POST/PUT/DELETE) and Kafka/JSON payloads to ensure seamless integration between supply chain modules.
- Reduced test data creation time by 90% by implementing reusable "Excel/CS to JSON" converters along with automated Kafka message posting to test IOT alerts module.

Associate Analyst | Jun 2022 – Mar 2024

- Spearheaded hyper care and product release support activities, including test effort estimation, test planning, and crafting detailed project synopsis documents, ensuring smooth post-release transitions utilizing tools like Jira and Confluence.
- Acted as a liaison between the Product team and Development team, managing communication and prioritization of critical scope tickets based on Agile methodology, reducing delays in project timelines.
- Received the Medallion Award for Outstanding Performance and Dedication in Q3 2022.

## **EDUCATION**

MBA - International Transportation & Logistics, Indian Maritime University, Chennai

- Dec 2020 Jun 2022 | 78.06% CGPA
  - As one of the Placement Team Coordinators, led the coordination of online & on-campus placement drives, facilitating efficient interactions between students and potential employers.
  - Operations Management Intern (Sept 2022 Oct 2022) | DP World, Chennai

BE - Mechanical Engineering, Jeppiaar Engineering College, Anna University, Chennai May 2015 - Apr 2019 | 68.8% CGPA

Project Intern (Dec 2018- Feb 2019) | Renault Nissan Automotive India PVT LTD

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- **Manual Testing**
- Automation testing
- SQL
- **Data Analysis**
- Core Java
- Selenium WebDriver
- TestNG
- Page Object Model

- Cucumber BDD
- API Testing (Postman)
- CI/CD (Jenkins)
- Defect Tracking (Jira, TestRail) **Data Analysis**
- **Project Management**
- Agile Methodology
- **Presentation Skills**

- Test Case Design
- **Problem Solving**
- Report Generation
- Team Coordination
- Supply Chain Management
- Communication & Collaboration
- **Problem Solving & Analysis**

## **CERTIFICATES**

- Oracle Database Foundations by LearnQuest (April 2024)
- Foundations: Data, Data, everywhere by Google (July 2024)
- Learning Data Analytics by National Association of State Boards of Accountancy (Aug 2023)
- Postman Intro to APIs, Start Your API Testing Journey With Postman Tool by Coursera Project Network Courses (Aug 2022)

#### **LANGUAGES**

Tamil, English, Kannada